# Miranda Ransom . Jarvis Consulting

I joined Jarvis right after graduatating with my BCS[H] - Computer Science from the University of Windsor. I've aimed to join my theoretical background with practical application through my exteracurriculars such as hackathons and joning the Google Developers Student Club as a core member. I've also had the opperunity to work with a local-non profit as part of their tech team developing a MERN stack application with the main goal of data collection and analysis. Looking forward I'm excited to solve problems through software, build things, and continue learning in such a vast field.

#### Skills

Proficient: Java, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git

Competent: Data structures and algorithms, Javascript, React, MongoDB (NoSQL), C

Familiar: CSS, Kotlin / Android development, C#, Python, Networking

### **Jarvis Projects**

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_MirandaRansom

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: This project is used to log linux data and tracks potential outages. The script running on the network switch collects hardware and usage data from the nodes and logs them into a postgresql database. The nodes send hardware data on start up and then usage data every minute by the use of a crontab. An outage is detected when a node has not sent at least 3 data points in the past 5 minutes found via an SQL select query.

### Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

• Twitter App:

• JDBC App:

• Grep App:

Springboot App [GitHub]: Not Started

Python Data Analytics [GitHub]: Not Started

Hadoop [GitHub]: Not Started Spark [GitHub]: Not Started

Cloud/DevOps [GitHub]: Not Started

#### Highlighted Projects

Ensamble: a web app for band and musician matching [GitHub]: Utalizing basic web technologies such as HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP, Ensamble is a web app for bands to post ads looking for other musicians to collaborate with and musicians to find gigs and collaborators.

The Hype Machine [GitHub]: The Hype Machine is a fun and silly hackathon project exploring the SonicPi language in which you can code music. A python scripts determines if an electric longboard is moving and when it is, plays the SonicPi coded music file.

#### Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-present): Complete SCRUM tickets under the agile methodology to build out multiple projects. Projects include a cluster monitor focusing on strengthening Linux and RDBMS skills.

Tech Team Member, Windsor Essex Community Compassion Care (2020-2021): Build out an all encompassing MERN stack web application to aid in business needs. My focus was on the front end working with React, Material UI, Survey is and Chart is to design components (pages) to aid in user profiles, data collection, and analysis.

Teaching Assistant, University of Windsor (2020-2021): Held weekly office hours to aid students in understanding material and debugging code. Duties also included marking assignments while providing meaningful feedback and virtual in-class assistance

## Education

University of Windsor (2017-2021), Bachelor Computer Science [Honours], Computer Science - GPA: 84%

## Miscellaneous

- LinkedIn PowerBI Essential Training (2020)
- Guitarist
- Fiction and Non-fiction reader